# Susy **Echeverria-Londono, PhD**

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

@ susyelo@gmail.com

- +33 6 36 01 15 45
- susyelo.github.io
- ⋈ Paris area, France

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Multidisciplinary researcher with 10+ years of experience at the intersection of biodiversity, public health, and environmental science. Expert in synthesising and communicating complex research findings to scientists, policymakers, and broader audiences. Adept at managing and organising international events. Strong skills in scientific synthesis, data visualisation, and collaborative leadership across Europe, the Americas, and international consortia (e.g., WHO, GAVI, NSF, VIMC).

#### **SKILLS**

- Tools: R, Python, spatial and statistical analysis, Git, LaTeX, Excel and Office Suite.
- Leadership of international research projects and publications (e.g. VIMC, NSF-funded)
- Experience in delivering presentations and writing reports to diverse audiences, including scientists, policy makers, and the general public.
- Experience with bilateral and international cooperation (latinamerica and the United Kingdom).
- Great ability to synthesise complex data into accessible insights.
- Proactive and well-organized, with strong prioritization skills and a collaborative team spirit.
- Multilingual (Native in Spanish, professional competence in English and intermediate level in French/Italian).

### **INTERESTS**

Outside of work, I enjoy dancing, having regular walks with my dog and family, and volunteering at dog shelters.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# RESEARCH CONSULTANT (FREELANCE) Global/Remote

2022- now

- Supported policy-making institutions in assessing the potential for harmonizing and integrating vaccine impact estimates across platforms.
- Communicate findings through reports with global health stakeholders (VIMC, GAVI and BMGF).

## RESEARCH CONSULTANT AND RESEARCH ASSOCIATE Imperial College London, UK

2019-2022

- Analysed, organised, and prepared time series vaccine impact estimates for 12 pathogens across 112 countries from 21 models developed by institutions worldwide
- Ensured robust and policy-relevant outputs for decision-making in global health and produced regular technical reports to inform stakeholders and support evidence-based vaccine investment and advocacy.
- Drafted regular briefing notes and reports informing strategic investment decisions for global vaccination programs. PI: Prof. Neil M. Ferguson and Line manager: Dr Katy Gaythorpe

### NSF POSTDOCTORAL ASSOCIATE Kenyon College, OH, USA

2017-2019

- Demonstrated advanced skills in spatial data analysis and handling large ecological datasets by conducting in-depth quantitative analysis of functional diversity among plant species across North and South American biomes.
- Co-developed and taught an international module on "Global Ecology and Biogeography."
- Performed spatial data analysis on 300 plant species using spatial point pattern analysis.
- Analysed datasets comprising 85,000 plant species and over 9 million georeferenced data points. PI: Prof. Andrew Kerkhoff and Prof. Brian J. Enquist

### LECTURER AND DEMONSTRATOR

2013-2017

Natural History Museum Imperial College London, UK

- Coordinated field-based data collection and analysis between Colombian researchers and UK institutions.
- Contributed to high-level scientific diplomacy, presenting biodiversity findings to political leaders including the Colombian president, ministers and HRH Prince Charles.

### **EDUCATION**

Рн.D. in Life Science Imperial College London, UK.

2013-2017

M.RES. WITH DISTINCTION in Biodiversity, Informatics and Genomics Imperial College London, UK. 2012–2013

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BIOLOGY. 1st-class honours. *Universidad Industrial de Santander, Colombia*. **2004–2010** 

### **SELECTED PROJECTS & ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Managed the weekly delivery of high-level reports to stakeholders (WHO, GAVI, BMGF), meeting strict deadlines.
- Participated and help organising international working meetings, coordinated multi-country datasets, and supported framework agreement development.
- Managed data acquisition and international communication for biodiversity monitoring initiatives between Colombian and european researchers ensuring bilateral cooperation (e.g., the PREDICTS).
- 30+ peer-reviewed articles in Lancet, Nature, eLife, Vaccine (see https://susyelo.github.io/publications.html).
- Awarded Outstanding Paper by Young Investigator (ISE, 2022).